# ANATOLY YAKOVENKO

aeyakovenko@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | resume

## **SUMMARY**

Software developer with over 10 years of experience in embedded operating systems, shipping software on millions of units, developing <u>patents</u>, leading projects and contributing to large groups including <u>Linux Kernel</u>, with a focus on performance and optimization for Qualcomm ARM and DSP processors.

### **SKILLS**

# Hardware and Systems

 Embedded Operating Systems, RTOS, Linux Kernel, Android, Qualcomm MSMs, System MMUs, ARM, Hexagon DSP

# Languages and Tools

• C, Haskell, Make, Lua, Python, Ruby, Bash, C++, Java, Git, Perforce, GDB, JTAG, Trace32

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Qualcomm, San Diego CA

Senior Staff Engineer Manager, 2015 to Present Senior Staff Engineer, 2012 to 2015 Staff Engineer, 2008 - 2012 Senior Engineer, 2006 - 2009 Engineer, 2003 - 2006

#### OpenDSP

- Lead Architect of a brand new technology for utilizing DSP subsystems on Qualcomm chipsets for next-generation high-performance applications.
- Commercial applications include Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality, 3D Camera processing, 4K video post-processing, and GoogleX's Project Tango.
- Technology used by all major OEMS, such as Samsung, LG, Google, Xiaomi, OnePlus.

#### **BREW**

- Core kernel developer for BREW's Operating System.
- Built critical features such as application sandboxing, device driver framework, interprocess communication, system call tracing tools, IDL compiler for network transparent objects.
- Shipped to thousands of different handsets and in millions of units.

#### **QChat**

- Software developer for server components of a Push2Talk service.
- Implemented various network protocols such as SIP/RTP/HTTP, and high performance logging and tracing tools for a large distributed system with over 40 components.

#### Alescere LLC, Lisle IL

#### Co-Founder, 2001 to 2003

• Founding member of Alescere, a VoIP startup

 Lead development of SIP and <u>RTP</u> protocol stacks and server components for a VoIP system for small businesses.

# University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

## Research Assistant, 2003

- Developed a web server that supports QoS for HTTP requests
- Designed a probabilistic scheduler for the Linux kernel
- Implemented a roaming protocol for 802.11a/b networks for NetBSD

#### Personal Research

 Neural Networks, Genetic Algorithms, Markov Models, and Bayesian Inference Algorithms

# References

- Brian Kelley, Senior Director of Technology, bkelley@quicinc.com
- Rob Walker, Senior Director of Engineering, <a href="mailto:rwalker@quicinc.com">rwalker@quicinc.com</a>
- Ramesh Chandrasekhar, Senior Director of Engineering, <a href="mailto:rameshc@qti.qualcomm.com">rameshc@qti.qualcomm.com</a>

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2003